Hi, Neil, how are you I'm very well Thank you, Georgie, Are you enjoying your coffee I am but it's got a bit cool now I prefer my coffee hot,
But oh well are you enjoying yours I've finished mine Oh that's a shame It's a sad moment when I've finished my second coffee of the day
Because that's it I don't have more than two So we're talking about coffee in this episode aren't we We are.
But before we start, of course, everyone needs to know that there is a free worksheet on our website that's atbbclearningenglish.com. Yes, they can also find a free transcript can't they they can yes at the same address?
So Georgie,
We're talking about coffee, how much coffee or how many coffees if we're talking about cups of coffee.
How many do you have a day, I usually have two, and I know that you do as well because we drink them both in the office, don't we, We have one cup of coffee in the morning and one.
Usually in the afternoon, when we need to regain some energy and alertness Yeah, and so we all know because we make each other.
At BBC learning English we make each other coffee so we know how we take our coffee Yes, how we take our coffee is how we like it, what we like to put in it.
For example, sugar or milk, I know that you don't like milk in your coffee, you take your coffee black, I do, I like black coffee and you take your coffee white.
And you used to have sugar, but you don't anymore That's right occasionally when I'm at home, I put some honey in my coffee to make it a bit sweeter U
Honey and coffee Yes, is that surprising?
I never heard of that really sugar, but not honey, but why would that be so bad Well, I don't know it's just I've never heard of it it's really good.
I would recommend, okay, so Georgie, what happens if you don't have your coffee Well, in the morning, if I don't have coffee, I feel very grumpy.
And very tired in the afternoon, if I don't have a coffee, it's not terrible,
But I would prefer to have my afternoon coffee, How about you, Yeah, I need my coffee.
Especially in the morning, but I don't have my coffee first thing in the morning Oh interesting, I have it kind of, I don't know, work time nine o'clock.
Why is that I think it's too strong, too powerful or maybe just the way I drink it what happens if you drink too much coffee Oh then it's difficult
To sleep because of the caffeine caffeine is that chemical in coffee and tea that makes you feel awake and alert
But too much means you're too alert I don't think that caffeine has a big effect.
On me I don't think I have trouble sleeping if I drink too much coffee, it's strange yeah because sometimes I'll have an espresso after dinner
Really, yeah, and I can still sleep That's crazy Yeah lucky me lucky you Neil,
Have you ever tried to cut down on coffee cut down on you mean, have less No, I haven't tried to cut down on coffee, but I've tried to cut down.
On caffeine, Okay, so I for a while, I only drank decafeinated coffee or decaf as we call it, Okay, and how was that Well, I didn't.
Miss caffeine at the time, I don't think it lasted for a long time, but now I drink caffeine, I don't care.
Okay, Neil, it's time to recap the vocabulary we used in the conversation.
We use the verb take so Neil, how do you take your coffee I take my coffee black and I know you take your coffee white.
Yes, we also heard caffeine, which is the chemical that is in coffee which makes you feel more awake Yes,
But you can also get decafeinated coffee or tea it means there's no caffeine and we usually,
Short on that just to decaf decaf coffee.
Yes, we also heard the phrasal verb cut down on, which means you have less of something.
Yep, and you can also say cut back on it means the same thing.
Okay, well that is the end of this conversation about coffee in real easy English Yes and if people want to watch more episodes of real easy English, what should they do?
They should go to our website BBCclearningenglish.com. where they can find a free worksheet to test what they've learned goodbye for now goodbye.